[KARA]
Hello, Noah?
[NOAH]
It’s a go!
Kara!
So many blessings!
Isn’t the universe amazing?
- It always knows the perfect timing...
- Don’t. You’re going to make me cry.
- Thanks, Carol.
- I love you.
[KARA]
Super thank you.
- [CAROL SQUEALS]
- [PEARL] Isn’t it nice here, Mom?
Of course.
- We’re here to celebrate Kara.
- Yes!
[WAITER] Sorry, we have a
private gathering tonight.
[WAITER]
So we are closed.
[SANTI] Seriously?
We came all the way here,
now you’re
telling us to leave?
Hi, there.
I’m Santi.
Excuse me?
[SANTI] You’re lucky
I even gave you attention!
- [SANTI] Huh?
- [HAN BIN] Hey! Stop!
Hey!
[PEARL]
Sir Han!
[MUFFLED YELLING]
[JAO]
Kara!
[KARA]
How’s Pearl?
[JAO]
She’s okay.
How about you?
I thought I was okay.
What happened back there
brought everything back.
Thank you for earlier.
If it’s for you,
I don’t mind getting hurt.
[PEARL CLEARS THROAT]
[JAO] I know it's hard for you
to trust people, but I’m here now.
I’m not going anywhere.
I love you, Kara.
[BICYCLE BRAKES SQUEAK]
[JAO]
Beautiful.
Like a painting.
This is better
because it’s real.
And it’s right in
front of our eyes.
4,800 hectares of mangroves.
One of the biggest
in the world.
[SIARGAONON]
Absolutely beautiful.
And soon enough,
Cabitoonan will look like this too.
There’ll be a lot more
Ruths out there, right?
- Yeah.
- [JAO AND KARA LAUGH]
And you’ll help us plant them.
Of course!
I already promised, didn't I?
You know, there's an
old saying from our elders.
[JAO SPEAKS SIARGAONON]
Two people in love
who watch the
sunrise together
will…
always find their way...
back to each other
like the waves
meeting the shore.
Exactly.
It’s a beautiful story.
And I believe in
beautiful things.
[JAO] I have faith
in beautiful things.
Me, too.
This is the point of life.
Watching the sun rise with…
…with the person you love.
I love you, Jao.
No matter what happens,
no matter where
life takes us,
always remember,
as long as the waves
find their way back to shore,
I’ll always love you.
[ALON BY JL]
- [PEARL] Oh! Good day, sir!
- Hello.
- Checking in?
- Yes.
Do you have
a reservation?
Yes.
It’s under Carina Flores.
She’s my friend.
She booked this place for me.
Okay.
[PEARL]
Oh. There you go.
- One room under Carina Flores.
- [GUEST] Yeah.
[PEARL]
Well, welcome to Katig, sir.
Let me guess...
Korean.
Yes.
Very good guess.
[PEARL GIGGLES]
Yes. Because the owner of this hotel,
my boss, he’s Korean, too.
[GUEST]
Ah, wow. Fantastic.
I’d love to meet him.
Where’s he?
Oh, he’s going to be
here in a few minutes.
But in the meantime,
can I have your
passport, please?
[GUEST]
Yeah, sure.
[PEARL SPEAKS KOREAN]
Thank you.
- [PEARL LAUGHS]
- [GUEST] Thank you.
[WAVES CRASHING]
[SIARGAONON]
Good morning, everyone!
I’m Ariel,
your island bestie.
While I was delivering
sarongs today,
I came across this booth
promoting mangrove protection.
We’re here at...
Shield the Mangroves,
Official Protector.
- Say hi to our ambassadors!
- Hello!
All proceeds will go to
mangrove conservation efforts.
It's really a community effort!
- Wow!
- Yes.
- Okay, let’s sign up.
- Okay.
- Thank you.
[ARIEL] Even the official sign-up
already comes with a loot bag!
Wow!
Huge thanks to our sponsors!
Thank you,
Shield bath soap.
Sign up now,
island besties!
Till our next vlog!
Bye!
[ARIEL]
Oh...
Ariel, thank you so much
for promoting this event.
- We’re so grateful!
- Anytime. Anything for the island.
- Yes.
- You should join, too.
Of course I will!
This Menthol Cool is my favorite.
It’s refreshing on the skin.
- That one’s great.
- This one, too.
- That, too. It’s nice.
- Menthol Cool’s great on the skin.
- Smells good, too.
- This is Honey and Orange Blossom.
- Yes.
- Sounds like it smells good.
I’ll try that next time.
[KOREAN]
Stop it already.
The guy you sent is
trying to take me back!
[HAN BIN’S SISTER] We respect
your decision to stay in the Philippines.
[HAN BIN SIGHS]
Listen carefully.
I’m satisfied living
here right now.
I’m not going
back to Korea.
So don’t call me.
[HAN BIN’S SISTER]
But you have to come home.
Father is in the hospital.
What?
You’re saying
Dad’s in the hospital?
[HAN BIN’S SISTER]
He’s very, very sick.
[HAN BIN SIGHS]
How's Mom?
[HAN BIN’S SISTER]
Come home, young brother.
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
[PEARL]
Sir!
Sir Han.
We have a Korean guest
and he wants to meet you.
I know.
Oh...
You’re expecting Sir Won?
Whatever happens, Pearl,
please know that...
everything that I’ve
ever shown you was real.
Uh...
[PEARL LAUGHS]
What’s...
What’s happening?
Did something happen?
Do I need to know anything?
There’s a lot of things
I need to tell you, but...
I never found the
right opportunity.
I thought there was
always another time, but...
nothing’s guaranteed
in life and…
Sir Han.
Can you just please
go straight to the point?
I like you, Pearl.
A lot.
Since the first time
I laid my eyes on you.
But you didn’t say anything.
I have my reasons.
Kara’s right.
You are crazy!
No, I just didn’t want things
to be awkward between us.
But you didn’t say anything!
You deserve to know now.
I don’t know what to say.
Pearl...
I’m not expecting
anything in return.
I want you to concentrate
on chasing your dreams.
If we are
meant to be together,
fate will find a way.
Wait, you’re confessing,
but why does it feel like you’re...
[PEARL BREATHES DEEPLY]
you’re saying goodbye?
Maybe because...
you’ll be taking
your Masters abroad.
I won’t say goodbye.
I’ll see you again.
So, a Korean guy
showed up at Katig Hotel,
and that gave Han Bin
the courage to confess?
But…
he’s not asking you out?
[CAROL]
How does that work?
He just...
- dropped a bomb on you.
- Exactly, Mom!
That’s it!
That's exactly how I feel!
So what am I
supposed to think now?
[CAROL]
Think?
Pearlita!
The real question is…
how do you feel about him?
I know you’re just pretending
to deliver sarongs at Katig
so you can talk to Sir Han.
Of course.
I want to know if he’s
serious about you.
You’re the confusing one.
I've known for ages
that he likes you.
So?
Does he have a chance?
How would I know?
Well...
did you sleep
at all last night?
How could I, Ariel?
After everything
he told me?
[PEARL SIGHS]
Now I don’t even know how
to act when I see him at Katig.
Hm...
Did he ask if you like him?
No.
That’s the weird part.
He said,
“I like you, Pearl.”
Hm.
But the way he said it sounded
like he was saying goodbye.
I couldn’t sleep
because of that.
Hey, Tantan!
- Tantan!
- [TANTAN] Hey, Pearl.
[TANTAN] I drove
Sir Han earlier today.
He was with
your Korean guest.
Where?
To the airport.
T​​hey’re flying back to Korea.
- [ARIEL] Huh?
- Airport?
He didn’t even say goodbye?
[TANTAN] He said there was
a family emergency in Korea.
Uh...
He left some reminders
to you via email.
Pearl, check it!
Read the email.
What does it say?
[PEARL BREATHES DEEPLY]
His father is in the ICU.
And he doesn't know
when he’ll be back
- or if he’ll come back at all.
- [TANTAN] Huh?
My gosh.
He said he’ll send
a new manager.
A new manager?
Because he’s sure
I’m going to Switzerland.
Sorry, Pearl.
Sir Han really
is confusing.
[ARIEL] We're here today
at Barangay Cabitoonan
for the first day of our planting
ceremony for the mangrove reserve.
You should plant the first one
because this project wouldn’t
be possible without you.
Let Egay do it.
Egay.
Why me?
Because what we’re
doing here today is for you.
For the children of Siargao.
Team Mangroves forever!
[CROWD CHEERS]
[CROWD CHANTING]
Team Mangroves! Team Mangroves!
[KARA]
Who did this?
It’s really disturbing how
these people see paradise
and only think of profit.
I’m sorry, okay?
I don’t mean to offend you.
I’m not generalizing either.
- But surely there are...
- Wait, wait.
[WOMAN]
Kara, I'm sorry.
The Mayor won't be able
to meet with you today.
But come back tomorrow.
Kara, look at this.